Guide to the Bud Titsworth Commercials, 1968-1991 and undated
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Bud Titsworth Commercials 1968-1991 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Titsworth, C. Dayton (Charles Dayton)
3.0 Linear Feet 19 Items
C. Dayton Bud Titsworth was an executive at Lord, Geller, Federico, Einstein, a subsidiary of the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) advertising agency, in the 1970s and 1980s, before starting his own agency.
The Bud Titsworth Commercials collection span the years 1968-1991 and consist of audio tapes, videocassettes and 16mm films of radio spots and television commercials on which Titsworth worked. Clients represented include Canada Dry, IBM, STP and Warner-Lambert. Announcers for radio spots include sportscaster Howard Cosell. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In addition, original audiovisual materials are closed to patron use. Research Services staff need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Bud Titsworth Commercials were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2009.
Biographical Note
Chronology List
Born Charles Dayton Titsworth, Greenwich, Conn.
1965 BA, Syracuse University
1965-1968 Marketing and Research Departments, Young & Rubicam
1968-1971 Account Executive, Ted Bates and Company
1971-circa 1986 Account Representative, later Account Manager, J. Walter Thompson Company; later Senior Vice President, Lord, Geller, Federico, Einstein, Inc.
Circa 1986-1996 Titsworth & Company
1996- Director, Westport Consulting
Collection Overview
The Bud Titsworth Commercials collection span the years 1968-1991 and consist of audio tapes, videocassettes and 16mm films of radio spots and television commercials on which Titsworth worked. Clients represented include Canada Dry, IBM, STP and Warner-Lambert. Announcers for radio spots include sportscaster Howard Cosell.
Collection Arrangement
Arranged by format, alphabetically therein.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Titsworth, C. Dayton (Charles Dayton)
Cosell, Howard, 1918-1995
J. Walter Thompson Company
Lord, Geller, Federico, Einstein, Inc
Canada Dry Corporation
International Business Machines Corporation
STP Corporation
Warner-Lambert Company
Advertising
Advertising -- History
Advertising -- United States -- History
Advertising agencies
Advertising agencies -- United States
Advertising executives
Advertising executives -- United States
Radio advertising
Television advertising
Audio tapes
Videocassettes
16mm
Titsworth, C. Dayton (Charles Dayton)
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Contents of Collection
- Bud Titsworth Commercials, 1968-1991 and undated
  Restrictions on Access: Original audiovisual materials are closed to patron use. Research Services staff need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed.
  - Howard Cosell Listerine label reading. Undated. Format: 1/4 audiotape. TRT: 3:00 (Box 1)
  - Radio spots. Undated. Format: 1/4 audiotape. TRT: 6:00
  - J. Walter Thompson, STP spots. Undated. Format: 16mm. TRT: 0:30
  - STP sales film out takes. 1978 May. Format: 16mm. TRT: 10:00
  - STP sales film out takes. Undated. Format: 16mm. TRT: 10:00
  - Titsworth reel: Wink, Galaxy, Carpet Brite, Chiclets, Listerine. Undated. Format: 16mm. TRT: 23:00
  - Captain of America: Rock and a Hard Place, Rolling Stones Commemorative Coin rough cut. 1990 Jan. 12. Format: Umatic. TRT: 30: 00 (Box 2)
  - Corning: Hectic World, Pizza Crisper, Range Toppers, French White. Undated. Format: Umatic. TRT: 10:00
  - J. Walter Thompson, STP spots. 1978 June 30. Format: Umatic. TRT: 3:30
  - Lord, Geller, Federico, Einstein: IBM PC spots. 1981-1984. Format: Umatic. TRT: 9:00
  - Lord, Geller, Federico, Einstein: IBM/Entry Systems Division. Undated. Format: Umatic. TRT: 6:00
  - Panel Productions: Rand Levine, Heublein, Babycham, Introductory Sales Film with commercials. Undated. Format: Umatic. TRT: 10:00
  - STP sales film. 1978 June 19. Format: Umatic. TRT: 10:00
  - Titsworth reel: Canada Dry (Wink), Warner-Lambert (Chiclets, Listerine), STP. Undated. Format: Umatic. TRT: 5:00
  - Titsworth reel: Wink, Chiclets, Listerine, STP. 1968-1978. Format: Umatic. TRT: 10:00
  - STP sales film1991 Aug. 26. Format: VHS. TRT: 10:00
  - STP sales film out takes. Undated. Format: VHS. TRT: 30:00
  - Titsworth reel: IBM, LA Longshoreman, STP, Subaru, Volvo, Xerox, AT&T, Levi, Chanel. Undated. Format: VHS. TRT: 12:00
  - Titsworth reel: Wink, Galaxy, Carpet Brite, Chiclets, Listerine. Undated. Format: VHS. TRT: 30:00